Ever wanted to be someone else? Now you can.
Being John Malkovich is a comedy, drama, fantasy film directed by Spike Jonze.
One day at work, unsuccessful puppeteer Craig finds a
portal into the head of actor John Malkovich.
The portal soon becomes a passion for anybody who enters its mad and
controlling world of overtaking another human body.
Craig Schwartz, played by John Cusack.
Lotte Schwartz, played by Cameron Diaz.
John Horatio Malkovich, played by John Malkovich.
Maxine Lund, played by Catherine Keener.
Dr. Lester, played by Orson Bean.
Floris, played by Mary Kay Place.
Being John Malkovich is a 1999 American surrealist fantasy comedy drama film directed by Spike
Jonze and written by Charlie Kaufman, both making their feature film debut.
The film stars John Cusack, Cameron Diaz, and Catherine Keener,
with John Malkovich as a version of himself.
Cusack plays a puppeteer who finds a portal that leads into Malkovich's mind.
Released by USA Films, the film received widespread acclaim, with praise for its
writing and direction, and grossed $23 million against a $13 million budget.
The film was nominated in three categories at the 72nd Academy Awards: Best
Director, Best Original Screenplay, and Best Supporting Actress for Keener.
The film ranked 441st on Empire magazine's 2008 list of the 500 greatest films of all time, while Malkovich's
performance is ranked number 90 on Premiere's "100 Greatest Movie Characters of All Time".
The film explores themes of witch, sexual identity,
individual, secret love, transvestism.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.